# Paul Young Junior Full Stack Developer

Newcastle UK 07792 871106 youngjpj@gmail.com paulio11 on GitHub & LinkedIn

### **Profile**

I am a graduate of Teesside University and Code Institute, with a decade of experience in customer-facing roles and team leadership. My educational background has revolved around IT, from high school to university and beyond. I am proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Python. My true passion lies in computing, technology, and the video games industry. I am excited to finally embark on a career in a field that I love, where I can contribute, grow, and make a difference.

#### **Education**

June 2022 - June 2023 Diploma in Full Stack Software Development

Code Institute - Dublin, Ireland

Credit rated by University of West Scotland

September 2005 - June 2008 Bachelor of Arts Degree in Computer Games Art

Teesside University, School of Computing

September 2002 - June 2004 A Levels in Information Technology (A), and Art & Design Graphics (A)

Plus General Studies, History and an AS Level in Psychology

September 1999 - June 2002 CGSEs in Mathematics (A), Art Graphics (A), Design & Technology (B),

Science Double Award (B)

11 in total including English, English Literature, German, Geography, History and

Physical Education

## **Portfolio Projects**

Pokébox <a href="https://github.com/paulio11/P5-Pokebox">https://github.com/paulio11/P5-Pokebox</a>

A React application where users can track their Pokémon collection, interact with other users, and stay up to date with the latest Pokémon news and information.

Interacts with my own API as well as PokéAPI.

Pokébox API <a href="https://github.com/paulio11/P5-Pokebox-API">https://github.com/paulio11/P5-Pokebox-API</a>

A back-end API built using the Django Rest Framework.

Squigl https://github.com/paulio11/P4-Squigl-Twitter-Clone

A social network based on Twitter, complete with all features including trending,

hashtags, mentions, moderation and more. Built using Django.

Co-op Today <a href="https://github.com/paulio11/Co-op-Today">https://github.com/paulio11/Co-op-Today</a>

Mobile web app with scheduling, messaging, and to do list functionality. Styled to fit with current company applications. Built using Django. Made in a few hours as a

concept.

Hangman <a href="https://github.com/paulio11/P3-Hangman-Python-Terminal-Game">https://github.com/paulio11/P3-Hangman-Python-Terminal-Game</a>

A game that runs in a Python Terminal, uses a Google Sheet to store words and

player scores.

Co-op Your Pay <a href="https://github.com/paulio11/P2-Co-op-Your-Pay">https://github.com/paulio11/P2-Co-op-Your-Pay</a>

A website for Co-op employees to calculate their pay and learn more about it. The

main functionality is built using JavaScript.

## **Work Experience**

January 2020 - Present Team Leader, Co-op Food

In my current role I am responsible for all members of staff and the store. Guiding learning and development, and providing advice and support when needed.

Planning and supervising duties for my team.

May 2011 - December 2019 Customer Team Member, Co-op Food

Promoting services and assisting customers with their needs. This role

demonstrated my flexibility, communication and listening skills. I worked as part of

a large team and excelled.

#### References

**Jordon Dixon** Store Manager, Co-op Food

07792 980014

Owonikoko Oluwaseun Mentor, Code Institute

https://github.com/seunkoko

Maureen Kristen Tutor

01669 621251

Barry Gibson NGFA Chairman

07737 641985